Guide to the Samuel R. Pierce papers, 1961-1985.
Pierce, Samuel R. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Samuel R. Pierce papers, 1961-1985.
6531
Samuel R. Pierce 1922-
ca. 40 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, printed material, publications, videos, plaques
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Memorabilia and papers of Samuel R. Pierce from his Treasury Board appointment in 1970 to his later years as Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Samuel R. Pierce was born September 8, 1922 in Glen Cove, New York, and served in the U.S. Army during and after the Second World War (1943-1946). He obtained his A.B. with honors from Cornell (1947), his law degree in 1949 from the Cornell Law School and earned his LL.M. in taxation (1952) at New York University School of Law. After being admitted to the New York Bar in 1949 he served as assistant district attorney of New York (1949-1953). Pierce was first lieutenant judge advocate general corps, reserve (1950-1952), assistant U.S. attorney, Southern District New York (1953-1955), assistant undersecretary of the Department of Labor during President Eisenhower's first term (1955-1956), and he served as associate counsel of the Council of the Judicial Subcommittee on Anti-Trust for the U.S. Supreme Court (1956). For a brief time, Pierce was a member of the U.S. House of Representatives (1956-1957). He then earned his J.D. and conducted postgraduate work at Yale Law School from 1957 to 1958. Pierce also served as a judge of the New York Court of General Sessions (1959-1961). He was very active in practicing private law, doing so on and off for well over twenty years (1957-1959, 1961-1970, and 1973-1981), at one time becoming a partner of Battle, Fowler, Pierce and Kheel. He was also on the faculty of New York University from 1958 to 1970. Pierce worked as general counsel and head legal director of the U.S. Department of the Treasury from 1970 to 1973 and served as Secretary of Housing and Urban Development in the Reagan Administration from 1981 to 1989. He was the first African American to serve in Ronald Reagan's Cabinet. Pierce died on October 31st, 2000.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Memorabilia, plaques, degrees, awards and recognitions, appointment books, scrapbooks, speech transcripts, biographies, flyers, clippings, photographs, audio and video tapes documenting the career of Samuel R. Pierce from his Treasury Board appointment in 1970 to his later years as Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). Includes correspondence relating to his legal career, Treasury papers and HUD records. Also court case studies, academic publications, magazines, calendars, booklets, pamphlets, news articles, government documents (HUD and Treasury related), scrapbooks, ceremony and event ephemera, federal orders, and Boy Scout badges.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pierce, Samuel R., 1922-; Pierce, Samuel R., 1922-; Reagan, Ronald.; United States. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development -- Management.; United States. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development -- Planning.; United States. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development -- Officials and employees.
Places:
United States -- Politics and government -- 1981-1989.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restrictions on access and use to be determined pending negotiations with the donor.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Information
Box 1-2
Series II. Legal Career
Box 3-5
Court Documents
Court Notes
Appointment Books
Miscellaneous Booklets
Miscellany
Series III. Department of Treasury
Box 5
Series IV. Department of Housing and Urban Development
Box 5-7, 42
Series V. Speeches
Box 18-19
Series VI. Memorabilia
Box 20-21
Series VII. Photographs
Box 28, 34, 39, 41, 44, Mapcase
Series VIII. Certificates
Box 34, 36, 40-44
Series IX. Degrees
Box 34, 39-42, 44, Mapcase
Series X. Orders
Box 34, 36, 39, Mapcase
Series XI. Awards and Gifts
Box 22-27, 30, 34-47, Mapcase
Series XII. Scrapbooks
Box 8-17
Series XIII. Audio Cassettes, 1981-1988
Box 29
Series XIV. Video Cassettes, 1981-1988
Box 29-32
Series XV. Miscellaneous Material
Box 33
RELATED MATERIALS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Information
  - Election for Judge of the Court of General Sessions NY County, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Application to Columbia University Law School, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chart: Clearance of CBS/NBC Programs in 40 Common "Must-buy" Markets, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - HUD Egypt, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - HUD Housing Tax Discussion, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Remarks and Statements by Samuel R. Pierce, 1970-88 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Subscription Television, 1955-58 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Frank H. T. Rhodes, 1992-95 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cornell, 1957-99 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - African-American Involvement, 1959-74 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News Release, 1955-89 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Itineraries, 1982-86 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New York University Law, 1958-66 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Richard Nixon Library and Birthplace, 1993-94 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Resumes, No Date (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The White House, 1970-89 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Politics, 1960-93 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Antitrust Laws, 1956-58 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - George Bush, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ronald Reagan, 1958-99 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Nelson Rockefeller, 1959-67 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lockheed Bailout, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Richard Nixon, 1971-73 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letters and Telegrams on Appointment to General Sessions, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - George W. Bush, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Coretta Scott King, 1986-89 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Scandal, 1987-95 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Made Partner in Battle, Fowler, Stokes, and Kheel, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Birth Certificate, 1922-94 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The US Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1982-95 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Memorandum (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Lots of notes and handwritten documents
  - Miscellaneous Correspondences (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Documents and Publications (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Robert F Wagner (Mayor), 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Equal Protection of Law, No Date (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Scandal Correspondence (See also SCANDAL in box 1), 1989-96 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Friends of Samuel R. Pierce Jr. Legal Defense Fund, 1990-91 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yale Law School, 1961-99 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Samuel J. LeFrak, Maryland University - First Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Copies of Material Given to Al McNeill on Recognition of Business Skills, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pierce Retirement, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Atlanta University, Morehouse College Real Estate Institute, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Network Broadcasting: Reprint of the Network Study Staff to the Network Study Committee, Volume 2, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Eagle Scouts, 1936-91 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Samuel R. Pierce Apartments, No Date (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - NY County Lawyer's Association, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Law Publications, 1957-73 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    The New Look in Collective Bargaining Agreements: A Study of Supplemental Unemployment Benefit Plans, Tax Refund Litigation in District Courts: Choice of Forum, Trial Procedures, and Settlement Techniques
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hoover Institution, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hofstra University, 1984-93 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Biographies of Samuel R. Pierce Jr., No Date (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series II. Legal Career
  - Court Documents
    - Hearing Before the Committee on Finance United States Senate, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hearing Before the Subcommittee on Postal Facilities and Mail, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - James McKeon, Cleo Smith, Howard Robinson, Reuben Lansky, Sherwood Cantine, Rufus Spruiell and Abner West Reply Brief of Respondents-Appellants, No Date (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Court Notes
    - Sandra Denise Johnson v. United States, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Schmerber v. California, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Murgia v. United States, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Terry v. Ohio, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - King v. United States, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Pedersen v. United States, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Wyman v. James, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Huguez v. United States, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Blackford v. United States, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Glaziou v. United States, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Rochin v. California, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Boyd v. United States, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Carroll v. United States, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Broland v. United States, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Castle v. United States, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Jimmy Savill v. United States and Rita Ann Guarrasi v. United States, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Witt v. United States, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Guadalupe-Garza v. United States, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Henderson v. United States, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Rivas v. United States, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Breithaupt v. Abram, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Landau v. United States, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Yee Engee How v. United States, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Colonade Catering Corp. v. United States, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bible v. United States, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cotzhausen v. Nazro, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Schwarts v. BMI, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Appointment Books
    - Daily Reminder, 1962-1969 (Box 3)
    - Photocopies of Appointment Calender, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Weekly-Minder Appointment Book, 1981-88 (Box 3)
    - Horses: A 1991 Calender, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Personal Memorandum, Cornell University, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Faraway Places: Calendar, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Real Peace: A Strategy for the West (signed copy by Richard Nixon), 1983 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Booklets
    - Telluride Association, Directory of Associates, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Dinner of Champions, Long Island Sports Hall of Fame, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Securities Investor Protection Corporation, First Annual Report, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Glen Cove High School, Clip Board 1940 - 1990, 1990 (Box 5)
    - The Collective Bargaining Forum 1969, 1969 (Box 5)
    - The Institute for Civil Justice, A Report on the Organizational Phase July 1979 - March 1980, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Bar Association of Nassau county, N. Y., Inc., Eighty-Ninth Annual Dinner, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Wisdom Hall of Fame, No Date (Box 5)
    - YMCA, 117th Anniversary Annual Dinner, 1969 (Box 5)
    - The Unsung Hero of the Reagan Revolution, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Constructor, Managing Construction Equipment, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Inauguration of President and Vice President, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Salute to Greatness Dinner 1989, 1989 (Box 5)
    - American Military Engineers, Military - Industrial Conference, 1956 (Box 5)
    - The New York Republican County Committee, Presidential Lincoln Day Dinner and Victory Ball, 1981 (Box 5)
    - National Review, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Response of Personal Data Questionnaire by Samuel Riley Pierce Jr., No Date (Box 3)
    - Hearings Before Subcommittee No. 5 of the Committee on the Judiciary House of Representatives, 86th Congress 2nd Session, 1960 (Box 3)
    - The Television Inquiry, Television Network Practices Report, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Labor Arbitration and Dispute Settlements Decisions and Recommendations, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Hearings Before the Antitrust Subcommittee of the Committee, Part 2 - Volume 4 Television, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Hearings Before the Antitrust Subcommittee of the Committee, H. R. 264 and H. R. 2143, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Committee on the Judiciary House of Representatives, Television Hearings (In Two Volumes) Vol. 1 Parts 1 and 2, 84th Congress, 1957 (Box 3)
    - The Television Inquiry, Part II UHF-VHF Allocations Problem, Testimony of Public and Industry Witnesses, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Organized Professional Team Sports on H. R. 5307, H. R. 5319, H. R. 5383, H. R. 6876, H. R. 6877, H. R. 8023, and H. R. 8124, Part 3, 1957 (Box 3)
    - United States of America v. Sandra Denise Johnson, 1970 (Box 3)
      - Petition for a Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, 1970 (Box 3)
      - Brief for the United States (Box 3)
      - Respondent's Brief, 1970 (Box 3)
      - Appendix, 1970 (Box 3)
    - New York Times Co. v. Sullivan, 1963-65 (Box 3)
      - The Anatomy of an Historic Decision: New York Times Co. v. Sullivan, 1965 (Box 3)
      - Brief for the Petitioners, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Sadie H. Markham, 1963 (Box 3)
      - Petitioner's Reply to Respondent's Brief in Opposition, 1963 (Box 3)
      - Petition for a Writ of Certiorari to the Supreme Court of North Carolina, 1963 (Box 3)
    - The Procter and Gamble Independent Union of Port Ivory, N. Y., v. The Procter and Gamble Manufacturing Company, 1962 (Box 3)
    - National Hockey League Players' Association v. Boston Professional Hockey Association, Inc., et al., 1957 (Box 3)
    - New York University Bulletin, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Response by Samuel R Pierce Jr. to Questionnaire for Prospective Nominees for United States Circuit Judgeship, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - New York Times vs Sullivan, 1962-65 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - New York University vs. Students for a Democratic Society, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series III. Department of Treasury
  - Department of the Treasury News, 1971-73 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Background Briefing for the Cabinet on the President's Tax Program, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Department of Justice, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The General Counsel of the Treasury, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bills, Acts, Amendments, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Department of the Treasury, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dinners, Memorandum, Itineraries, 1970-72 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Treasury Remarks, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Treasury Resignation and News Clippings, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Department of Housing and Urban Development
  - HUD Housing Dinner, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - HUD 1984 Budget Review, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - HUD 1984 Budget Review, Community Planning and Development: Budget Review Group Comments, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - HUD 1984 Budget Review, Community Planning and Development: Budget Review Group Comments, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - HUD 1984 Budget Review, Solar Energy and Energy Conservative Bank: Budget Review Group Comments, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Budget Review Group Comments on 1984 Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Budget Review Group Comments on 1984 Administration, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Budget Review Group Comments on 1984 Office of Inspector General, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Budget Review Group Comments on 1984 Housing Programs, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - HUD 1985 Budget and Legislative Review Housing Programs, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - HUD 1988 Budget and Legislative Review Housing Submissions, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - HUD 1989 Budget OMB Hearings Highlights, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 1986 Budget Potential Questions and Answers for Selected Programs, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - HUD Congressional Justification for 1986 Estimates (Part 1), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - HUD Congressional Justification for 1986 Estimates (Part 2), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - HUD Congressional Justification for 1986 Estimates (Part 3), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cooperative Program on Building Construction and Urban Planning between The United States and The People’s Republic of China Second Meeting and Study Tour in The United States 15-24 October 1981, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Battery Park City, 1968-78 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Battery Park City Authority Series A Bond, New Issue, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Federal National Mortgage Association Privatization Study, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - HUD Book Info, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - HUD News Clippings, 1960-86 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Howard University School of Business, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1983 OECD (Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Secretary Pierce Press Interviews, 1988-89 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Accomplishments of Samuel R. Pierce Jr., 1983-85 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Government National Mortgage Association Secretary's Briefing Book, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Fannie Mae REMICs, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - HUD Notes, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - HUD Remarks, 1983-88 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - HUD News Releases, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - HUD Miscellaneous Papers Part 1, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - HUD Miscellaneous Papers Part 2, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - HUD Miscellaneous Memos and Correspondences, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - HUD Records, February 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - HUD Records, March 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - HUD Records, April 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - HUD Records, May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - HUD Records, June 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - HUD Records, July 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - HUD Records, August 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - HUD Records, September 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - HUD Records, October 1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - HUD Records, November 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - HUD Records, December 1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - HUD Records, January 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - HUD Records, February 1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - HUD Records, March 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - HUD Records, April 1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - HUD Records, May 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - HUD Records, June 1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - HUD Records, July 1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - HUD Records, August 1982 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - HUD Records, September 1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - HUD Records, October 1982 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - HUD Records, November 1982 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - HUD Records, December 1982 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Series V. Speeches
  - Speeches: January 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: February 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: March 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Speeches: April 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Speeches: May 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: June 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Speeches: July 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Speeches: August 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Speeches: September 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Speeches: October 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Speeches: November 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Speeches: December 1983, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Speeches: January 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Speeches: February 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Speeches: March 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Speeches: April 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Speeches: May 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Speeches: June 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Speeches: July 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Speeches: August 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Speeches: September 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Speeches: October 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Speeches: November 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Speeches: December 1984, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Speeches: January 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: February 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: March 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Speeches: April 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Speeches: May 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: June 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Speeches: July 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Speeches: August 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Speeches: September 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Speeches: October 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Speeches: November 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Speeches: December 1985, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Speeches: January 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Speeches: February 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Speeches: March 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Speeches: April 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Speeches: May 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Speeches: June 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Speeches: July 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Speeches: August 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Speeches: September 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Speeches: October 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Speeches: November 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Speeches: December 1986, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Speeches: January 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Speeches: February 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Speeches: March 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Speeches: April 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Speeches: May 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Speeches: June 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Speeches: July 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Speeches: August 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Speeches: September 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Speeches: October 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Speeches: November 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Speeches: December 1987, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Speeches: January 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Speeches: February 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Speeches: March 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Speeches: April 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Speeches: May 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Speeches: June 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Speeches: July 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Speeches: August 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Speeches: September 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Speeches: October 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Speeches: November 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Speeches: December 1988, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 48)
- Series XI. Memorabilia
  - Kienzle Quartz Clock, No Date (Box 20)
  - DBS Bank - Silver Plate (Box 20)
  - Lockheed TriStar Model Airplane, No Date (Box 20)
  - JET Ticker Tape U.S.A. Clock, 1984 (Box 20)
  - Public Housing Authorities Directors Association - Clock, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Letter Opener and Shear Set, No Date (Box 20)
  - Key to the City of Huntsville, Alabama, No Date (Box 20)
  - Ronald Reagan Inauguration Miniature Axe, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Federal National Mortgage Association - Guaranteed Mortgage Pass-Through Certificates, Series 1982-1 (Box 20)
  - Miniature Liberty Bell, No Date (Box 20)
  - Jefferson Junior High School - Stationary Holder (Box 20)
  - YMCA of Greater New York, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Boys Clubs of America - Magnifying Glass, No Date (Box 20)
  - The United States of America - Medal "A Vision For The Nation", No Date (Box 20)
  - Presidential Task Force - Medal of Merit, No Date (Box 20)
  - United States Savings Bonds - Paper Weight, No Date (Box 20)
  - YMCA of Greater New York - Paper Weight, No Date (Box 20)
  - National Association of Real Estate Brokers - Paper Weight, No Date (Box 20)
  - U.S. Customs Treasury Department - Badge, No Date (Box 20)
  - Freedom National Bank of New York - $3,755,000 Capital Notes and Preferred Stock record (Box 20)
  - The Official 1985 Presidential Inaugural Medal, 1985 (Box 20)
  - United States Attorney's Office - Medal "From His Friends In The United States Attorney's Office", 1955 (Box 20)
  - Boston Investment and Development Co. Stamford Green Groundbreaking, Stamford, Connecticut - Paper Weight, 1982 (Box 20)
  - National Industrial Conference Board Inc. - Medal, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Damaged Memorabilia, No Date (Box 20)
    Empty box from Harvard, several name plates, plastic, metal, and wood stands
  - Mount Holyoke College - Plate, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Elephant-shaped Paper Weight, No Date (Box 21)
  - Republican Senatorial Inner Circle - Glass Case, No Date (Box 21)
  - Pajaritos Autoctonos de Puerto Rico - Plate, Carpintero de Puerto Rico Printed, No Date (Box 21)
  - Decade of Disabled Persons - Goblet, 1985 (Box 21)
- Series XII. Photographs
  - Photos in France and Russia, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Photos of Awards, Plaques, and Memorabilia 1, No Date (Box 28, Folder 2)